Guide to the Van Broughton Ramsey Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
Van Broughton Ramsey Accessions
1980-2014
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Ramsey, Van Broughton
2019.007
36 Linear Feet
32 boxes
The archive of Emmy-award winning costume designer, Van Broughton Ramsey spans 1980-2014 and measures 32 boxes. The bulk of the collection comprises his design binders for various projects; these are arranged according to genre: plays, films, television movies, television mini-series, and television series.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Van Broughton Ramsely, 2019
Scope and Contents
The archive of Emmy-award winning costume designer, Van Broughton Ramsey spans 1980-2014 and measures 32 boxes. The bulk of the collection comprises his design binders for various projects; these are arranged according to genre: plays, films, television movies, television mini-series, and television series. There is one binder for his work designing the walk-around costume McGolf, an official mascot of the PGA. There are also several binders containing detailed research files, most arranged by decade, but some by project (boxes 24-27).
The collection includes numerous original sketches for his projects. Many are housed within the design binders (boxes 2-23), but there are also a number of sketches in folders in box 1 and in oversized boxes 28-32. Character plots (charts used to plan costumes and budgets) are likewise housed within some binders, but there are also several oversized in box 32.
Some other highlights of the collection are letters from Lilian Gish, Bill Wittliff, and Glenn Close; the booklet from the Costume Designer's Guild's career achievement award which Ramsey was awarded in 2009; playbills from numerous productions; and clippings and ephemera relating to his work.
Index Terms
Subjects
Theater; Film; Costume design -- Notebooks, sketchbooks, etc; Feature films; Television mini-series
Document Types
Television scripts
Subjects (Persons)
Ramsey, Van Broughton; Foote, Horton; Close, Glenn; Tyson, Cicely
- Accession 2019-007
  Scope and Contents
  The archive of Emmy-award winning costume designer, Van Broughton Ramsey spans 1980-2013 and measures 32 boxes. The bulk of the collection comprises his design binders for various projects; these are arranged according to genre: plays, films, television movies, television mini-series, and television series. There is one binder for his work designing the walk-around costume McGolf, an official mascot of the PGA. There are also several binders containing detailed research files, most arranged by decade, but some by project (boxes 24-27).
  The collection includes numerous original sketches for his projects. Many are housed within the design binders (boxes 2-23), but there are also a number of sketches in folders in box 1 and in oversized boxes 28-32. Character plots (charts used to plan costumes and budgets) are likewise housed within some binders, but there are also several oversized in box 32.
  Some other highlights of the collection are letters from Lilian Gish, Bill Wittliff, and Glenn Close; the booklet from the Costume Designer's Guild's career achievement award which Ramsey was awarded in 2009; playbills from numerous productions; and clippings and ephemera relating to his work.
  - Resume, correspondence, awards, 1980-2009 (Box 2908, Folder 1)
  - Booklet from the Costume Designers Guild Career Achievement Award, 2009 (Box 2908, Folder 2)
  - Playbills, undated (Box 2908, Folder 3)
  - Clippings and ephemera (1 of 2), undated (Box 2908, Folder 4)
  - Clippings and ephemera (2 of 2), undated (Box 2908, Folder 5)
  - The Oldest Living Confederate Widow: Clippings, undated (Box 2908, Folder 6)
  - On Valentine's Day: Digital printout of female costume sketch, undated (Box 2908, Folder 7)
  - Bastards Out of Carolina: Cast photographs, Photo of Van Ramsey grilling, undated (Box 2908, Folder 8)
  - Sarah Plain and Tall: Skylark: 33 color photos (8x10) taken on set during filming. Includes 2 photographs of Van Ramsey, undated (Box 2908, Folder 9)
  - Comanche Moon: "Costumes of Comanche Moon" booklet, and clipping, undated (Box 2908, Folder 10)
  - Sarah Plain and Tall: Winter's End: 2 color photos (8x10) with Glenn Close and Christopher Walken, undated (Box 2908, Folder 11)
  - O Pioneers!: 4 photographs, undated (Box 2908, Folder 12)
  - Story of a Marriage" "My first play in NYC" Photograph of actors, undated (Box 2908, Folder 13)
  - The American Tempest: Polaroids, undated (Box 2908, Folder 14)
  - Costume Sketches, undated
    Sub-Series Description
    Costume sketches by Van Broughton Ramsey for a variety of plays and films.
    - Courtship: 10 original costume sketches, undated (Box 2908, Folder 15)
    - 1918: 23 original costume sketches, undated (Box 2908, Folder 16)
    - 1918: Photographs of Matthew Broderick and other cast members. Also photos of On Valentines Day, and Mary Steenburgen in End of the Line, undated (Box 2908, Folder 17)
    - Habitation of Dragons: 7 original costume sketches; 14 "color plot" pages, undated (Box 2908, Folder 18)
    - Dangerous Corner: 4 original costume sketches, undated (Box 2908, Folder 19)
    - The Would-be Gentleman: 1 original costume sketch, undated (Box 2908, Folder 20)
    - Einstein and the Polar Bear: Playbill, 13 original costume sketches, undated (Box 2908, Folder 21)
    - Lily Dale: 4 original costume sketches, undated (Box 2908, Folder 22)
    - Valentine's Day: 2 original costume sketches, undated (Box 2908, Folder 23)
    - Lonesome Dove: 1 original costume sketch for Clara, undated (Box 2908, Folder 24)
    - "Costumes for my agent's children" Wizard, Leprechaun, Ritual robe, undated (Box 2908, Folder 25)
  - Plays, 1988-2014
    Binders containing scripts, sketches, budgets, and character plots for a variety of plays. Arranged alphabetically by play title.
    - Frankie and Johnny are Married. Written and directed by Michael Pressman (Black 3" binder), 2003 (Box 2909, Item 1)
    - The Habitation of Dragons. Written by Horton Foote. Pittsburgh Public Theatre Production (Black 3" binder), 1988 (Box 2909, Item 2)
    - Hello Again. "Play" The Blank Theatre Company, Hollywood, California. (Blue 1" softcover binder), undated (Box 2909, Item 3)
    - Hello Again. "Play-Musical" (Black 1" binder), undated (Box 2909, Item 4)
    - Roberto Zucco. Written by Bernard-Marie Koltès; directed by Russell Milton (Black 1" binder), undated (Box 2909, Item 5)
    - The Trip to Bountiful "Play on Broadway." Written by Horton Foote; directed by Michael Wilson. Starring Cicely Tyson, Cuba Gooding, Jr., Vanessa Williams, and Condola Rashad (White 3" binder), 2013 (Box 2909, Item 6)
    - The Trip to Bountiful. Script for Broadway production (Orange 1" binder), 2013 (Box 2909, Item 7)
    - The Trip to Bountiful. Rehearsal script for Broadway production (Black 1" binder), 2013 (Item 2910, Item 1)
    - The Trip to Bountiful "Play at Ahmanson, L.A." Written by Horton Foote; directed by Michael Wilson. Starring Cicely Tyson, Blair Underwood, and Vanessa Williams (Black 1.5" binder), 2014 (Item 2910, Item 2)
    - The Trip to Bountiful. Performance script for Ahmanson production, Los Angeles (Black 1" binder), 2014 (Item 2910, Item 3)
    - The Trip to Bountiful. "CTG-LA Play" CTG Casting Shop (Blue 1" binder), undated (Item 2910, Item 4)
    - Horton Foote's The Trip to Bountiful. "TV Movie" Prepared by Hallie Foote and Michael Wilson, directed by Michael Wilson. Starring Cicely Tyson, Blair Underwood, and Vanessa Williams (Black 1" binder), 2014 (Item 2910, Item 5)
    - The Widow Claire "Off-Broadway Play." Written by Horton Foote, directed by Michael Lindsay-Hogg and starring Matthew Broderick. Circle in the Square Theatre, New York (Blue 3" binder), 1986 (Item 2910, Item 6)
    - The Widow Claire "Play: NY" Screenplay by Horton Foote (Teal 1" binder), 2004 (Item 2910, Item 7)
    - Wooden Breeks "Play in L.A." Written by Glen Berger (Black 3" binder), 2001 (Item 2910, Item 8)
  - Films, 1987-2013
    Binders containing scripts, costume sketches, research materials, production notes, and other documentation for film projects. Arranged chronologically by broadcast date of the films.
    - Courtship. Written by Horton Foote, directed by Howard Cummings and starring William Converse-Roberts, Horton Foote, Jr., Hallie Foote, and Daisy Foote. "Drawing for my first movie with Horton Foote." (Small black 1" binder), 1987 (Box 2911, Item 1)
    - Courtship. (Black 3" binder), 1987 (Box 2911, Item 2)
    - End of the Line. Directed by Jay Russell and starring Kevin Bacon and Mary Steenburgen. (Red 3" binder), 1987 (Box 2911, Item 3)
    - Silent Tongue. Written and directed by Sam Shepard, starring Alan Bates, Richard Harris, Joaquin Phoenix, and Dermot Mulroney. (Black 3" binder), 1993 (Box 2911, Item 4)
    - The Stars Fell on Henrietta. Directed by James Keach and starring Robert Duvall. Script. (Lavender 1" binder), 1995 (Box 2911, Item 5)
    - The Stars Fell on Henrietta. Directed by James Keach and starring Robert Duvall. (Navy 3" binder), 1995 (Box 2912, Item 1)
    - The Tripper. Written by and directed by David Arquette and starring Arquette and Courtney Cox. (Maroon 2" binder), 2006 (Box 2912, Item 2)
    - Albert Nobbs. "I only did the screen test in L.A., but not the movie in Ireland." Directed by Rodrigo García and starring Glenn Close. (Black 2" binder), 2011 (Box 2912, Item 3)
    - All is Lost. Written and directed by J. C. Chandor and starring Robert Redford. (Blue 3" binder), 2013 (Box 2912, Item 4)
    - All is Lost. Script. (White 1" binder), 2013 (Box 2912, Item 5)
    - A Night in Old Mexico. Written by William D. Wittliff and directed by Emilio Aragón; starring Robert Duvall. (Black 3" binder), 2013 (Box 2913, Item 1)
    - A Night in Old Mexico. Research. (Black 3" binder), 2013 (Box 2913, Item 2)
    - A Night in Old Mexico ["Skydance"]. Orders and receipts. (White 3" binder), 2013 (Box 2913, Item 3)
    - A Night in Old Mexico ["Skydance"]. Orders and receipts. (Gray 2" binder), 2013 (Box 2913, Item 4)
    - A Night in Old Mexico. Script. (Black 1" binder), 2013 (Box 2913, Item 5)
    - A Night in Old Mexico ["Skydance"]. Script. (Blue 1" binder), 2013 (Box 2913, Item 6)
    - This Isn't Happening (Independent short). Written by Thomas Carty and Russell Milton; directed by Carty. (Blue 1" binder), 2012 (Box 2914, Item 1)
    - "Jane" (unproduced). "Slated film starring Melanie Griffith and Howard Stern: ended in law suit." (Red 3" binder), undated (Box 2914, Item 2)
    - "Lily Dale" (unproduced). "Postponed, and I did not design the movie." (Black 3" binder), undated (Box 2914, Item 3)
    - "Lily Dale" (unproduced). Screenplay by Horton Foote. (Black 3" binder), undated (Box 2914, Item 4)
    - "Of Scent of Mind" (unproduced). Written by Niklaus Hilber and Drew Bird. (Black 2" binder), undated (Box 2914, Item 5)
    - "A Walk in the Woods" (unproduced). Written by Michael Arndt, based on Bill Bryson's memoir. (Maroon 1" binder), undated (Box 2914, Item 6)
  - Television Movies, 1992-2010
    Binders containing scripts, costume designs, research, photographs, and other production materials for television movies. Arranged chronologically by broadcast date.
    - Sarah, Plain and Tall. Directed by Glenn Jordan and starring Glenn Close and Christopher Walken. (Black 3" binder), 1991 (Box 2915, Item 1)
    - Our Sons. Directed by John Erman and starring Ann-Margret, Julie Andrews and Hugh Grant. (Black 3" binder), 1991 (Box 2915, Item 2)
    - Aftermath: A Test of Love. Directed by Glenn Jordan and starring Richard Chamberlain and Michael Learned. (Black 3" binder), 1991 (Box 2915, Item 3)
    - O Pioneers! Directed by Glenn Jordan and starring Jessica Lange and David Strathairn. (Black 3" binder), 1992 (Box 2915, Item 4)
    - The Secret. Directed by Karen Arthur and starring Kirk Douglas. (Black 3" binder), 1992 (Box 2916, Item 1)
    - Sarah Plain and Tall: Skylark. Directed by Joseph Sargent and starring Glenn Close and Christopher Walken. (Black 3" binder), 1993 (Box 2916, Item 2)
    - House of Secrets [Conspiracy of Terror]. Directed by Mimi Leder and starring Cicely Tyson, Melissa Gilbert, and Bruce Boxleitner. (Black 3" binder), 1993 (Box 2916, Item 3)
    - Spring Awakening. Based on Willa Cather short story, "Resurrection." Directed by Jack Gold and starring Sherilyn Fenn and Jamey Sheridan. (Black 3" binder), 1994 (Box 2916, Item 4)
    - The Substitute Wife. Directed by Peter Werner and starring Farrah Fawcett, Lea Thompson and Peter Weller. (Black 3" binder), 1994 (Box 2917, Item 1)
    - The Road to Galveston. Directed by Michael Toshiyuki Uno and starring Cicely Tyson and Piper Laurie. (Black 3" binder), 1996 (Box 2917, Item 2)
    - The Road to Galveston. Cast and crew list. (Black 2" binder), 1996 (Box 2917, Item 3)
    - The Christmas Tree. Directed by Sally Field and starring Julie Harris, Trini Alvarado and Andrew McCarthy. (Red 3" binder), 1996 (Box 2917, Item 4)
    - The Bastard Out of Carolina. Based on novel by Anne Meredith. Directed by Anjelica Huston and starring Jennifer Jason Leigh, Ron Eldard, Glenne Headly, Lyle Lovett, Dermot Mulroney, and Christina Ricci. (Blue 3" binder), 1996 (Box 2918, Item 1)
    - The Bastard Out of Carolina. Script, first draft polish. (Red 1" binder), 1996 (Box 2918, Item 2)
    - The Tempest. Shakespeare adaptation directed by Jack Bender and starring Peter Fonda, John Glover, and Katherine Heigl. (Black 4" binder), 1998 (Box 2918, Item 3)
    - The Tempest. Script and continuity breakdown. (Black 2" binder), 1998 (Box 2918, Item 4)
    - The Tempest. Continuity breakdown and Polaroids. (Black 4" binder), 1998 (Box 2918, Item 5)
    - And the Beat Goes On: The Sonny and Cher Story. Adaptation of Sony Bono's book directed by David Burton Morris and starring Jay Underwood and Renee Faia. (Black 3" binder), 1999 (Box 2919, Item 1)
    - And the Beat Goes On: The Sonny and Cher Story. Costume chart and script. (Black 1" binder), 1999 (Box 2919, Item 2)
    - Sarah, Plain and Tall: Winter's End. Directed by Glenn Jordan and starring Glenn Close, Christopher Walken, and Jack Palance. (Black 3" binder), 1999 (Box 2919, Item 3)
    - Sarah, Plain and Tall: Winter's End. Costume chart and script. (Maroon 1" binder), 1999 (Box 2919, Item 4)
    - The Ballad of Lucy Whipple. Directed by Jeremy Kagen and starring Glenn Close, Jena Malone, Bruce McGill, and Meat Loaf. (White 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2919, Item 5)
    - The Ballad of Lucy Whipple. Scripts. (Black 1" binder), 2001 (Box 2919, Item 6)
    - On the Edge [The Other Side]. Written and directed by Mary Stuart Masterson and starring Anthony LaPaglia and Karen Sillas. (White 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2920, Item 1)
    - Material Girls. Directed by Martha Coolidge and starring Anjelica Huston and Hilary and Hayley Duff. (Black 3" binder), 2006 (Box 2920, Item 2)
    - Material Girls. Costume sketches. (Green 1" binder), 2006 (Box 2920, Item 3)
    - Material Girls. Script. (Black 1" binder), 2006 (Box 2920, Item 4)
    - Amish Grace. Directed by Gregg Champion and starring Kimberly Williams-Paisley (Orange 3" portfolio), 2010 (Box 2921, Item 1)
    - Amish Grace. (Purple 3" portfolio), 2010 (Box 2921, Item 2)
  - Television Mini-series, 1989-2008
    Binders containing scripts, costume designs, research, and other production materials relating to various television mini-series. Arranged chronologically by broadcast date.
    - Lonesome Dove. William D. Wittliff adaptation of Larry McMurty's novel, Directed by Simon Wincer and starring Robert Duvall, Tommy Lee Jones, Diane Lane, and Anjelica Huston. Fabric swatches. (Canvas Lonesome Dove 1: binder), 1989 (Box 2922, Item 1)
    - The Fire Next Time. Directed by Tom McLoughlin and starring Craig T. Nelson. (Black 3" binder), 1993 (Box 2922, Item 2)
    - The Fire Next Time. Orders and receipts. (Black 3" binder), 1993 (Box 2922, Item 3)
    - Oldest Living Confederate Widow Tells All. Directed by Ken Cameron and starring Diane Lane, Cicely Tyson, and Donald Sutherland. (Black 3" binder), 1994 (Box 2922, Item 4)
    - Buffalo Girls. Adaptation of Larry McMurtry's Novel by Cynthia Whitcomb. Directed by Rod Hardy and starring Anjelica Huston, Melanie Griffith, Gabriel Byrne, and Peter Coyote. (Black 4" binder), 1995 (Box 2923, Item 1)
    - Buffalo Girls. "Anjelica as Calamity Jane," continuity Polaroids (Black 3" binder), 1995 (Box 2923, Item 2)
    - Buffalo Girls. Continuity Polaroids (Black 3" binder), 1995 (Box 2923, Item 3)
    - The Feasts of All Saints. John Wilder adaptation of Anne Rice novel. Directed by Peter Medak and starring Robert Ri'chard, Peter Gallagher, Gloria Reubens, and Jennifer Beals. (White 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2924, Item 1)
    - The Feasts of All Saints. Script (Blue 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2924, Item 2)
    - Helen of Troy. Directed by John Kent Harrison and starring Emilia Fox, James Callis, and Daniel Lapaine. Costume designs 1 of 2 (Black 3" binder; pages damaged in flood and need to be iron pressed), 2003 (Box 2924, Item 3)
    - Helen of Troy. Costume designs 2 of 2 (Black 3" binder; pages damaged in flood and need to be iron pressed), 2003 (Box 2924, Item 4)
    - Helen of Troy. Script (White 3" binder), 2003 (Box 2925, Item 1)
    - Helen of Troy. Orders and receipts (Green soft-cover 1" binder), 2003 (Box 2925, Item 2)
    - Helen of Troy. Orders and receipts (Yellow soft-cover 1" binder), 2003 (Box 2925, Item 3)
    - Comanche Moon. Written by Larry McMurtry and Diana Ossana. Directed by Simon Wincer and starring Steve Zahn, Ryan Merriman, and Keith Robinson. (Black 3" binder), 2008 (Box 2925, Item 4)
    - Comanche Moon. Script. (Green 3" binder), 2008 (Box 2925, Item 5)
    - Comanche Moon. Research. (Black 2" binder), 2008 (Box 2926, Item 1)
    - Comanche Moon. Research. (White 2" binder), 2008 (Box 2926, Item 2)
    - Comanche Moon. Script. (Black 3" binder), 2008 (Box 2926, Item 3)
    - Comanche Moon. "The Costumes of Comanche Moon" Softcover booklet for Emmy consideration. "the sketch notebooks were lost in our move to N.Y.; these are the only sketches." (includes CD), 2008 (Box 2926, Item 4)
  - Television Series, 1992-2010, undated
    Binders containing scripts, costume designs, research, and other production materials for various television series. Arranged chronologically by broadcast date. Also included is the design binder for Billy McGolf, a walk-around character for the PGA.
    - Julie. Created by Irving and Ruthie Shatz, starring Julie Andrews. (Black 3" binder), 1992 (Box 2927, Item 1)
    - Ned Blessing: The True Story of My Life. Written and directed by William D. Wittliff, starring Daniel Baldwin, Chris Cooper, Brad Johnson. (Black 3" binder), 1992-1993 (Box 2927, Item 2)
    - Kate Brasher. Created by Stephen Tolken, starring Mary Stuart Masterson, Rhea Perlman, and Hector Elizondo. (Navy blue 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2927, Item 3)
    - Kate Brasher. Script (Blue 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2927, Item 4)
    - Kate Brasher. Script (Black 1" binder), 2001 (Box 2927, Item 5)
    - Brotherhood of Poland, New Hampshire. Written by David E. Kelly and starring Randy Quaid and Mare Winningham. "I designed the pilot but not the series." (Teal 2" binder), 2003 (Box 2928, Item 1)
    - The Book of Daniel. Created by Jack Kenny and starring Aidan Quinn. (Black 3" binder), 2006 (Box 2928, Item 2)
    - Glory Daze. Created by Walter Beck and Michael LeSteur. (Green 3" portfolio), 2010 (Box 2928, Item 3)
    - Glory Daze. 1980s research (Black 4" binder), 2010 (Box 2928, Item 4)
    - Glory Daze. Orders and receipts (Black 2" binder), 2010 (Box 2928, Item 5)
    - Glory Daze. Scripts, episodes 101-103 (White 3" binder), 2010 (Box 2929, Item 1)
    - Glory Daze. Scripts, episode 104 (Black 3" binder), 2010 (Box 2929, Item 2)
    - Glory Daze. Scripts, episode 105 (Blue 1" binder), 2010 (Box 2929, Item 3)
    - Glory Daze. Scripts, episode 106 (White 2" binder), 2010 (Box 2929, Item 4)
    - Glory Daze. Scripts, episodes 107-109 (Brown 2" portfolio), 2010 (Box 2929, Item 5)
    - Iron Chef: Showdown in Las Vegas. T.V. Pilot. (Black 3" binder), 2001 (Box 2930, Item 1)
    - "Bare Naked Ladies," "T.V. Pilot (not picked up)" (White 1" binder), 2005 (Box 2930, Item 2)
    - "Texas Graces" T.V. Pilot, (Red 1" binder), 1996 (Box 2930, Item 3)
    - "Travel Agency" [Misguided Tours] T.V. Pilot (Red 3" binder), undated (Box 2930, Item 4)
    - "Billy McGolf" Walk-around character for the PGA, 1999 (Box 2930, Item 5)
  - Research, undated
    Binders containing research on clothing, accessories, and styles for a variety of eras and also for a number of specific projects.
    - 1770-1820; Trappers, Shoes, Sioux, Arikawa, Mandans, Hidasta, Flatheads, Nez Perce, Chinoks (Green 3" binder), undated (Box 2931, Item 1)
    - 1845-1870s; Farmers, Indians, Texas Rangers, Slaves, Mexicans 1840s (Green 3" binder), undated (Box 2931, Item 2)
    - 1855-1870 (Green 3" binder), undated (Box 2931, Item 3)
    - 1830-1842; Women 1821-1822; Women 1825; Women 1830 (Black 4" binder), undated (Box 2931, Item 4)
    - 1830-1840; Men 1821-822; Men 1825, undated (Box 2932, Item 1)
    - Women 1899; Men 1899 (Black 3" binder), undated (Box 2932, Item 2)
    - 1930 (Black 3" binder), undated (Box 2932, Item 3)
    - 1902-1906 (Black 4" binder), undated (Box 2932, Item 4)
    - 1845-1850 (Black 2" binder), undated (Box 2933, Item 1)
    - Wedding, Jewelry, Shoes, Gloves, Children, Prairie (Black 3" binder), undated (Box 2933, Item 2)
    - Men's accessories; Women's accessories; Captains of Industry; Bully Boys; Old West: Cowboys; Old West: Characters; Farmers; Lawmen; Telegraph Operators; Lumberjacks/Trappers; Gravity People; Liberty People; Saloon People and Prostitutes; Stage Coach People; Railroad People; Immigrants; Slaves/Blacks, Trappers, Miners (Gray 3" binder), undated (Box 2933, Item 3)
    - New Orleans 1840-1843; French Army, Hattians, Children [likely for The Feast of All Saints]. (Black 3" binder), undated (Box 2933, Item 4)
    - Research for Goldrush: The Ballad of Lucy Whipple (Maroon 3" binder), undated (Box 2934, Item 1)
    - Research for Helen of Troy (Black 4" binder), undated (Box 2934, Item 2)
    - Research for Helen of Troy (Black 2" binder), undated (Box 2934, Item 3)
    - Research for The Oldest Living Confederate Widow Tells All (White 3" binder), undated (Box 2934, Item 4)
  - Oversized Original Sketches, 1982-2003, undated
    Original oversized watercolor sketches of costumes for various plays and film projects.
    - Dead Wrong: 5 costume sketches on watercolor board (10" x 13"), 1986 (Box 2935, Item 1)
    - The Troll Palace: 11 costume sketches on watercolor board (11" x 15"), 1985 (Box 2935, Item 2)
    - The Widow Claire: 2 costume sketches on watercolor board (11" x 15"), 1986 (Box 2935, Item 3)
    - Helen of Troy: 2 pages of sketches on paper (11.5" x 16.5"), 2003 (Box 2935, Item 4)
    - Valentines Day: 1 costume sketch on Cresent board (7.5" x 10"); 1 costume sketch on watercolor board (15" x 20"), 1984 (Box 2936, Item 1)
    - Wooden Breeks: 9 costume sketches on watercolor board (15" x 20"), 2001 (Box 2936, Item 2)
    - Outlaws, (Paul Hogan): 1 costume sketch on watercolor board (15" x 20"), 1992 (Box 2936, Item 3)
    - "Lady Marsden" 1 costume sketch on watercolor board (15" x 20"), undated (Box 2936, Item 4)
    - "Lucy. Diane Lane" 1 costume sketch on watercolor board (15" x 20"), undated (Box 2936, Item 5)
    - "Queen of Hearts" and "Queen of Swords" for Spanish television series: 2 costume sketches on watercolor board (15" x 20"), undated (Box 2936, Item 6)
    - American Tempest: 8 costume sketch on Crescent board (15" x 20"); 1 costume sketch (10" x 14); 1 costume sketch (8.5" x 11"), 1998 (Box 2937, Item 1)